Marion Nestle Papers, 1970-2017 MSS.159
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VII: Professional Activities, 268106
  - Subseries B: Teaching and Committees, 268111
    - Institute for Integrative Nutrition, Summer 2008; 269150 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - The Institute of Culinary Education, [2002-2011]; 269151 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Journal of Culinary Science & Technology: [Editorial Board Member], December 28, 2004; 269152 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - The Lancet - [Consultant], April-May 2005; 269153 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Les Dames d'Escoffier International Membership Directory, 2006; 269154 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Mauritius U.S. AID Consult, 1990; 269155 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Mauritius U.S. AID Consult - Final Report, 1990; 269156 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - NACSEX 1/90 Delegation: Cuba, 1992-1994; 269157 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - New School Food Studies Program, 1993-2001; 269158 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - The New York Food Museum, 2007; April 29, 1998; 269159 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - New York Hall of Science, 2005; 269160 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Nutrition: [Databases and Tools for Study of Nutrition], 1984; 1996; 269161 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Nutrition for Medical Professionals [1 of 2], [1990-2000]; 269162 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Nutrition for Medical Professionals [2 of 2], [1980-1989]; 269163 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Nutrition Education for Public Health (US) [1 of 2], [1995-2006]; 269164 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Nutrition Education for Public Health (US) [2 of 2], [1980-1995]; 269165 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Nutrition in Foreign Education, [1979-1983]; 269166 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Nutrition Education in Medical School [1 of 2], [1973-1979]; 269167 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Nutrition Education in Medical School [2 of 2], [1972-1992]; 269168 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Nutrition Education in Medical School [1 of 2], [1980-1985]; 269169 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Nutrition Education in Medical School [2 of 2], [1978-1981]; 269170 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Nutrition Summit, April 2009; 269171 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Nutritional Support, [1983-2007]; 269172 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - NYU - Chair Evaluation, July 15, 2004; 269173 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - NYU Department - Faculty Evaluation, January 26, 2003; 269174 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - NYU: New York University's Department of Nutrition Food & Hotel Management [1 of 2], 1985-1996; 269175 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - New York University, Department of Nutrition, Food & Hotel Management [2 of 2], 1993-1995; 269176 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - NYU: New York University Department of Nutrition, Food and Hotel Management Food Service Management (HOFD), 1992-1996; 269177 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - NYU - Department Policies and Memos [1 of 5], 1991-2001; 269178 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - NYU - Department Policies and Memos [2 of 5], 1991-2001; 269179 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - NYU - Department Policies and Memos [3 of 5], 1991-2001; 269180 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - NYU - Department Policies and Memos [4 of 5], 1988-1991; 269181 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - NYU - Department Policies and Memos [5 of 5], 1989-2001; 269182 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - NYU - Food Academics, 1997; 269183 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - NYU: Food Policy Course Material [1 of 2], 1992-1996; 269184 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - NYU: Food Policy Course Material [2 of 2], 1992-1996; 269185 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - NYU - Food Studies Cookbook Collection Fales Library and Special Collections, [2001-2002]; 269186 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - NYU Gardens, [2009]; 269187 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - NYU Green Grant, [2010]; 269188 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - New York University/Steinhardt School of Education Department of Nutrition and Food Studies - Food Academy Committee [1 of 2], 1997-2001; 269189 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - New York University/Steinhardt School of Education Department of Nutrition and Food Studies - Food Academy Committee [2 of 2], 1995-1998; 269190 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - NYU: Syllabus Draft: The Bitter and the Sweet: Puerto Rico, Sufar, and Caribbean History, January 4-16, 2004; 269191 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Office of Disease Prevention and Health Promotion: Appointment and Surgeon General's Report, [1986-1995]; 269192 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Oldways Preservation & Exchange Trust, [1999-2001]; 269193 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Pew Commission on Industrial Farm Animal Production, 2006; 269194 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - The Private and Public Scientific, Academic, and Consumer Food Policy Group (PAPSAC) [1 of 2], 2006; 269195 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - The Private and Public, Scientific, Academic and Consumer Food Policy Committee (PAPSAC) [2 of 2], [1996-2005]; 269196 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Resume, 1991; 269197 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Resume - NYU - Tenure Review, undated; 269198 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Science Board to the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, 2000; 269199 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Slow Food Nation, 2005-2007; 269200 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - SNAP to Health Meeting, 2012; 269201 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Teaching Kitchen Construction Plans and Information, 1995-1996; 269202 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - UC Berkeley Spring 2006, 2007 Materials, 269203 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - UCSF Souvenirs [1 of 2], 1976-1986; 269204 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - UCSF Souvenirs [2 of 2], 1976-1986; 269205 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Union of Consumed Scientists [1 of 2], [2005-2010]; 269206 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Union of Consumed Scientists [2 of 2], [2004-2005]; 269207 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - World Economic Forum, 2005; 269209 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - World Health Organization (WHO) [1 of 2], [2002-2006]; 269208 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - World Health Organization (WHO) [2 of 2], 2002; 269210 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - World Public - Certificate of Membership Health Nutrition Association, 2009-2011; 2012; 269211 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Subseries C: Lectures, 268155
    Subseries C: Lectures contains correspondence and programs related to lectures that Marion Nestle gave at various institutions worldwide.
    - University of California, San Francisco Lectures [1 of 3], circa 1980s; 269212 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - University of California, San Francisco Lectures [2 of 3], circa 1980s; 269213 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - University of California, San Francisco Lectures [3 of 3], circa 1980s; 269214 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - National Workshop on Nutrition Education in Health Professions Schools, September 30 - October 10, 1981; 269215 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Second United States-Nicaragua Colloquium on Health, October 1-4, 1984; 269216 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Shanghai Course [1 of 2], 1986; 269217 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Shanghai Course [2 of 2], 1986; 269218 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Proceedings of the Continuing Educaton Conference of State and Terretorial Public Health Nutrition Directors and Facilities of Graduate Programs in Public Health Nutrition - Surgeon General's Report, June 1-4, 1987; 269219 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Lectures and Conferences, 1988-1989; 269220 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Lectures, 1990; 269221 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Lectures and Conferences, 1991; 269222 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Lectures and Conferences [1 of 2], 1992; 269223 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Lectures and Conferences [2 of 2], 1992; 269224 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Lectures and Conferences, 1993; 269225 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Lectures and Conferences, 1993; 269226 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Conferences and Lectures, 1994; 269227 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Conferences and Lectures, 1994; 269228 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Lectures - Demand Strategies Proceedings Volume I, August 21, 1995; 269229 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Lectures [1 of 2], 1995; 269230 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Lectures [2 of 2], 1995; 269231 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Lectures/Events, 1996; 269232 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Lectures and Speaking Events, 1997; 269233 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Lectures: Conferences, 1998; 269234 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Lectures and Events, 1999; 269235 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Lectures and Conferences, 2000; 269236 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Lectures and Conferences, 2001; 269237 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Lectures and Conferences, 2001; 269238 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Lectures/Conferences, 2002; 269239 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Lectures and Events, 2002; 269240 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Lectures/Conferences, 2002; 269241 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Invited Lectures [1 of 3], 2003; 269245 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Invited Lectures [2 of 3], 2003; 269246 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Invited Lectures [3 of 3], 2003; 269247 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Invited Lectures [1 of 3], 2004; 269242 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Invited Lectures [2 of 3], 2004; 269243 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Invited Lectures [3 of 3], 2004; 269244 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Lectures [1 of 3], 2005; 269248 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Lectures [2 of 3], 2005; 269249 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Lectures [3 of 3], 2005; 269250 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - World Economic Forum Annual Meeting Participants Book, January 26-30, 2005; 271228 (Box 107, Folder 19)
    - Marion Nestle Visitor Passes, 2005-2011; 269251 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Lectures [1 of 3], 2006; 269252 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Lectures [2 of 3], 2006; 269253 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Lectures [3 of 3], 2006; 269254 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Events - 5th Annual Berkeley Public Library Foundation Author's Dinner, February 10, 2007; 269255 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Lectures [1 of 5], 2007; 269256 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Lectures [2 of 5], 2007; 269257 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Lectures [3 of 5], 2007; 269258 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Lectures [4 of 5], 2007; 269259 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Lectures [5 of 5], 2007; 269297 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Lectures [1 of 4], 2008; 269298 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Lectures [2 of 4], 2008; 269299 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Lectures [3 of 4], 2008; 269300 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Lectures [4 of 4], 2008; 269301 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Lectures: Chautauqua Foundation Lecture [Audience Response Questions], [2008]; 269302 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Marion Nestle & Michael Pollan: In Search of Real Food, April 18, 2009; 269303 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Events and Lectures, 2009; 269304 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Conferences and Lectures, 2009; 269305 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Lectures: January-May 2009 [1 of 2], 269306 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Lectures: January-May 2209 [2 of 2], 2009; 269307 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Lectures: June-December 2009 [1 of 2], 269308 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Lectures: June-December 2009 [2 of 2], 269309 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Lectures [1 of 4], 2010; 269310 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Lectures [2 of 4], 2010; 269311 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Lectures [3 of 4], 2010; 269312 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Lectures [4 of 4], 2010; 269313 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Conferences, 2010-2012; 269314 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - 2011 Lecture Materials, January-August, 269315 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Empowering the Nutrition Gatekeepers: From Parents to Products to Policy, July 23-26, 2011; 269316 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - 2011 Lecture Materials. September-December, 269317 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Lectures [1 of 3], 2012; 269318 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Lectures [2 of 3], 2012; 269319 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Lectures [3 of 3], 2012; 269320 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Subseries D: Reviewed Books, 268112
    Subseries D: Reviewed Books is comprised of manuscripts, advanced reading copies, and galleys for editorial and advisory review by Marion Nestle. Comments and correspondence with publishers regarding these books can be found in Subseries D: Correspondence.
    Material arrived together with no apparent order. The archivist arranged all books and manuscripts by surname of the author.
    - Manuscript: The Dinner Diaries: Raising Whole Wheat Kids in a White Bread World by Betsy Block, August 22, 2007; 269321 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Advance Reading Copy - Eat Naked by Margaret Floyd, February 15, 2011; 269322 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Ou of the East: Spices and the Medieval Imagination by Paul Freedman, 2008; 269323 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Advanced Draft - Eat Here: Defending Homegrown Pleasures in a Global Supermarket by Brian Halweil, July-November 2004; 269324 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - What to Do When No One Has a Clue by Stephanie Pierson and Barbara Harrison, 2010; 269325 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - The Mouse Diet - The No Hassle Way manuscript Dr. Frank Hansford-Miller, 2004; 269326 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Manuscript: Being Vegetarian for Dummies by Suzanne Havala, 2000; 269327 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Advanced Reading Copy: Hungary: A Mother and Daughter Fight Anorexia by Sheila & Lisa Himmel, 2008; 269328 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Advanced Reading Copy: StikkyWeight Management by Laurence Holt, 2003; 269329 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Rehearsal Draft: 36 Views by Naomi Iizuka, July 1, 2007; 269330 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Unedited Proofs - Scientific Criteria to Ensure Safe Food Institute of Medicine National Research Council, 2003; 269331 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript: The United States of Fat: Federal Food Policies that Undermined the Fight Against Obesity by Chin Jou, August 2011; 269332 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Advanced Reading Copy - The Flavor Point Diet by David L. Katz, August 23, 2005; 269333 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Advance Reading Copy: A Short History of the American Stomach by Frederick Kaufman, 2007; 269334 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Advance Reading Copy: Plenty by James MacKinnon and Alisa Smith, 2007; 269335 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - The Source: Unleash Your Natural Energy, Power Up Your Health, and Feel 10 Years Younger by Woodson Merrell, May 19, 2008; 269336 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Advance Reading Copy: Moveable Feasts by Sarah Murray, 2007; 269337 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Around the Table: Women on Food, Cooking, Nourishment, Love... And the Mothers Who Dished it Up For Them manuscript by Lela Nargi, December 1, 2004; 269338 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Meltdown: Fat-to-Finish in Record Time manuscript by Jamie Pandure, 2005; 269339 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - The World Is Fat by Barry Popkin, June 12, 2008; 269340 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - It's a Long Road to a Tomato manuscript by Keith Stewart, December 22, 2005; January 4, 2006; 269341 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript: The Triumph and Tragedy of Chicken [with comments] by Steve Striffler, June 21, 2004; 269342 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Mindless Eating by Brian Wansink, May 5, 2006; 269343 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Closing the Food Gap: Resetting the Table in the Land of Plenty by Mark Winne, June 23, 2007; 269344 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Subseries E: Correspondence, 268113
    Subseries E: Correspondence is comprised of professional e-mails, letters, thank you notes, and cards. A large portion of correspondence is in regards to Nestle's role as a book reviewer and consultant.
    - Nutrition in Clinical Practice Reviews and Correspondence, 1986; 269345 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991; 269346 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - [Articles and Letters Faxed to Dr. Nestle], 1990-1993; 269347 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - [Review Request from Ann Bramson], 1992; 269348 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995; 269349 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - Reviews, 1994; 269353 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Letters from Julia Child, October 2, 1995; 269350 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1996; 269351 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence [Editorial; Event], 1997-1998; 269352 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1997; 269354 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence [Editorial; Professional], 1998-1999; 269355 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Learning to Cook with Marion Cunningham [Invite to Book Launch], 1999; 269887 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 2001; 269357 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Professional, 2002; 269356 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 2003; 269358 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Interviews and Press, 2004; 269359 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: James Beard Events with Transcript of James Beard: A 20th Century Revolution in American Cuisine, May 3, 2004; 269360 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 2004-2005; 269361 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence [1 of 2], 2005; 269362 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence [2 of 2], 2005; 269363 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence on The Lancet editorial: Food Industry and Health: Mostly Promises, Little Action, 2006; 269364 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 2006; 269365 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - [Interview Confirmations], 2007; 269370 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Awards and Thank You's, 2007; 269366 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence [1 of 2], 2008; 269367 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence [2 of 2], 2008; 269368 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Interview Confirmations, 2008; 269369 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Invitation to the Inauguration of Barack Obama, January 20, 2008; 269371 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Journal Reviews, 2009; 269372 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence [1 of 2], 2009; 269373 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence [2 of 2], 2009; 269374 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Interviews and Press, 2009; 269375 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Interview Confirmations, 2010; 269376 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Interview Confirmations, 2010; 269377 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence [1 of 2], 2010; 269378 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence [2 of 2], 2010; 269379 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Thank-You's and Birthday Cards, 2010-2012; 269380 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2011; 269381 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 2011; 269382 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Thank You Cards and Holiday, 2012; undated; 269383 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Manuscript Reviews, 2012; 269384 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Interview Confirmation, 2012; 269385 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence [1 of 2], 2012; 269386 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence [2 of 2], 2012; 269387 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Subseries F: Grants and Awards, 268114
    Subseries F: Grants and Awards contains grant applications, information about award programs, and awards. Awards are both paper certificates, announcements in brochures, and three dimensional objects.
    Materials are arranged at the box level. Awards and Grants are described below chronologically.
    - Grand Application: NYU Clinical Coordinating Center, September 22, 1993; November 2, 1994; 269388 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Grant Application: Nutrition Adjunct Therapy in Prostate Cancer, 1997; 269389 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Grand Application: NYU Research Challenge Fund "Food Politics: The Food Industry and Public Health", 1997-1999; 269390 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Roundtable For Women in Food Service - NY Metro Chapter, October 6, 1997; 269393 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Grant Application: Feast + Famine Colloquium [1 of 2], 1999; 269391 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Grant Application: Feast + Famine Colloquium [2 of 2], 1999; 269392 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Awards: Harry Chapin Media Awards, 2002; 269394 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - "Honoring Marion" Guest Book, December 4, 2003; 269395 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - James Beard Foundation; American Anthropological Association, 2003; 269396 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Awards: The American Association for the Advancement of Science, September 20, 2004; 269397 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Awards: The American Association for the Advancement of Science, October 4, 2004; 269398 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Awards: American Society for Nutritional Sciences, April 4, 2005; 269399 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Awards - Les Dames d'Escoffier International, Summer 2005; 269400 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - The 2006 James Beard Foundation Awards Program, 269401 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Awards - Books for a Better Life, February 26, 2007; 269402 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Awards: James Beard Foundation, 2007; 269403 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Awards: James Beard Foundation, 2008; 269404 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Awards: The Robert Putnam Social Capital Award, May 1, 2010; 269405 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Certificate of Special Congressional Recognition National Hero, March 30, 2011; 269406 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Awards: Public Health Hero - University of California, Berkley School of Public Health, March 30, 2011; 269407 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - The James Beard Foundation Leadership Awards, October 17-18, 2012; 269408 (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - Subseries G: Planners, 268115
    Subseries G: Planners contains both weekly planners and Steno note pads with appointments and to-do lists.
    - 1976-1977 Weekly Planner; 1977-1978 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1976-August 31, 1977; July 1, 1977-August 31, 1978; 269409 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 1978-1979 Weekly Planner; 1979-1980 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1978-August 31, 1979; July 1, 1979-August 31, 1980; 269410 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 1980-1981 Weekly Planner; 1981-1982 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1980-August 31, 1981; July 1, 1981-August 31, 1982; 269411 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 1982-1983 Weekly Planner; 1983-1984 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1982-August 31, 1983; July 1, 1983-August 31, 1984; 269412 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 1984-1985 Weekly Planner; 1985-1986 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1984-August 31, 1985; July 1, 1985-August 31, 1986; 269413 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - 1986-1987 Weekly Planner; 1987-1988 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1986-August 31, 1987; July 1, 1987-August 31, 1988; 269414 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - 1988-1989 Weekly Planner; 1989 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1988-August 31, 1989; December 26, 1988-December 31, 1989; 269415 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 1989-1990 Weekly Planner; 1990-1991 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1989-August 31, 1990; July 1, 1990-August 31, 1991; 269416 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - 1991-1992 Weekly Planner, July 1, 1991-August 31, 1992; 269417 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - 2003-2004 Planners, 269418 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Steno Book Planner, February 4, 2003-February 9, 2004; 269419 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 2004-2007 Planners, 269420 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Steno Book Planner, February 23, 2004-November 8, 2005; 269421 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Steno Book Planner, November 8, 2005-June 7, 2008; 269422 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Weekly Planner 2007; Weekly Planner 2007-2008, January 1, 2007-August 1, 2007; July 1, 2007-August 31, 2008; 269423 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Weekly Planner 2008, December 31, 2008-January 4, 2009; 269424 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - 2009 Weekly Planner, December 29, 2008-January 3, 2010; 269425 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - 2009-2010 Weekly Planner, December 2009-December 2010; 269426 (Box 78, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: Press, 268107
  Series VIII: Press is comprised of press clippings, magazines, interviews, and articles which quote Marion Nestle or her books.
  Material is arranged chronoligcally.
  - Press: Clippings, 1989; 269427 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Press: Clippings, 1991; 269428 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Press: Clippings, 1992; 269429 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Press: Clippings, 1992; 269430 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Press: Clippings, 1992; 269431 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Press: Clippings, 1993; 269432 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Press: Clippings, 1994; 269433 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Press: Clippings, 1990; 269434 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Press: Clippings, 1995; 269435 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Press: Clippings [1 of 2], 1996; 269436 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Press: Clippings [2 of 2], 1996; 269437 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Press: Clippings, 1997; 269886 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Press: Clippings [for MN and NYU], 1998; 269905 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Press: Clippings, 1998; 269913 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Press: Original Magazines [1 of 2], 1999; 269914 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Press: Original Magazines [2 of 2], 1999; 269915 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Press: Clippings [1 of 2], 1999; 269916 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Press: Clippings [2 of 2], 1999; 269917 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Press: Clippings and Lectures, 2000; 269438 (Box 80, Folder 10)